# Bala Subrahmanyam Varanasi

Email: <u>vabasu@gmail.com</u> Mobile: +919819633692

## Summary

A Software Engineer with four years of professional experience in the areas of Development, Design and Management of various Web and Mobile applications using Python/Django, Ruby on Rails and Android. Also, an Open-Source Enthusiast who loves to learn and teach open source tools.

## **Experience**

Backend Developer at Glitterbug Technology, November 2015 – Present

## Software Engineer at TinyOwl Technology, April 2015 – November 2015

Responsible for developing and maintaining micro service applications using Ruby On Rails, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Redis, AWS and etc...

## Founder at Firebolt Labs, Aug 2014 – April 2015

Headed the day-to-day-operations, as well as handled the company's product and consulting projects.

## Software Developer at Crypsis Technologies, Sept 2013 - July 2014

Responsible for the development of web and mobile apps using various technologies like Ruby on Rails, Android and NodeJS

## Intern and Software Developer at Agiliq Info Solutions, Dec 2011 – Aug 2013

Worked with several clients across the globe on various projects and helped them in building various web and mobile apps using Python/Django and Android.

### **Interests**

FOSS, Web Development, Mobile Development and DevOps.

### Skills

Data Structures, Algorithms, Databases, Python, Django, Ruby on Rails, Ansible, GIT.

## **Projects**

#### **Open Source**

- Feature Development in django-graphos.
- Bugfixes and pep8 improvements in scikit-learn.
- pep8 improvements in joblib.
- <u>Sentiment Analyzer</u>, a simple sentiment classification tool for Telugu Language.
- Feature Improvements and Test Cases in Join.agiliq.com
- Improvments to code samples in DjenOfDjango.

## **Django Applications**

- <u>CoverFox Insurance</u>, an online insurance destination.
- <u>Sufo</u>, an Educational Video site for Physicians.
- Feature Developments in <u>Suggestar</u>.
- Customized the Django Admin CMS for <u>CineSport</u>, an innovative web video syndication company.
- Feature Development in <u>TravelDojo</u>, a company to create travel guides to the Southeast Asia region.
- Testing and Bugfixes Ocassio Health Strategies.
- Seeded <u>HyderabadWiki</u> with Wikipedia dump in LocalWiki Format.

• The Xaming Arena, a simple Online Examination system using Django framework.

## **Ruby on Rails Applications**

- TinyOwl, a food ordering application.
- Mr Delicious, an online food delivery system.
- <u>Investment Club</u> by <u>StockViews</u>.
- Feature Development in <u>Swym</u>.
- <u>Virtual Analyst</u> by <u>Analytics Intelligence</u>.
- Feature Developments and Test Cases Development in Mega Golf Virtual League.

### **Android Applications**

- "Windows Ambassador", an application by Microsoft.
- "Where's My App?", checks the availability status of apps and games in the Windows Phone Store.
- "Baby Names", a simple android app to choose a baby name.

## **Publications**

"Python Requests Essentials", a book which showcases fundamental as well as advanced Python Requests concepts. (ISBN-10: 1784395412) (ISBN-13: 978-1784395414)

## **Education**

- Batchelor of Technology, Information Technology from Vishnu Institute of Technology, 2008 2012.
- **Intermediate Education** from Santhiniketan Junior College, 2006 2008.
- SSC from G.V&K.B.M School, 2006.

# As a Speaker

PyCon India, 2013; SciPy 2011 & 2013 and CoDec 2012.